<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | The Dutch Android User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.dutchaug.org/meetups/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.dutchaug.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-26T07:31:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.dutchaug.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Foundation the Dutch Android User Group]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[info@dutchaug.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can hack, but you can't hide!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.dutchaug.org/blog/2013/11/24/droidcon-hackathon/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.dutchaug.org/blog/2013/11/24/droidcon-hackathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sunday November 24th 2013 | 9am - 9pm | Science Park Amsterdam</p>

<p><em>The Dutch Android User Group and droidconNL invite you to join the coolest Android hackathon event of the year!</em></p>

<p><strong>Location, location, location</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><em>Are you a savvy Android developer or designer but have little time to play around with all the cool new Google Play APIs
and Android features? Or are you lacking inspiration or quality time to think up the next generation Android apps?
If you can't hide your enthusiasm for Android and just enjoy building great Android apps this event is for you!
Sign up and be inspired by your teammates and fellow contestants and measure your Android skills in a single day
Android hackathon event, just before the biggest Android conference in The Netherlands, droidconNL!</em></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/meetups/dutchaug-android-hackathon-2013-poster-2-flattened.png"></p>

<h2>Location, location, location:</h2>

<p>The hackathon will be held on <strong>Sunday November 24th</strong> at the droidconNL 2013 venue;
<strong>Science Park Amsterdam</strong>. We open the doors at <strong>9am</strong> and explain the process and rules and start the hackathon a
little after that.
Then you have until <strong>8pm</strong> to finish up your Android app and present it to a jury of Android experts.
Apart from great prizes you'll win eternal glory for winning the second DutchAUG hackathon and you can brag about your
winning Android app for a whole year! At the end of the hackathon all contestant are invited to the "<em>after-the-hack party</em>"
 for an informal meet &amp; greet with droidconNL speakers, sponsors and VIPs.</p>

<h2>How can I join?</h2>

<p>You can sign-up at <a href="http://www.droidcon.nl">http://www.droidcon.nl</a> starting from Monday July 29th at 10am! We will allow 12 teams to register for this event so be sure to
register sooner rather than later if you want to enter the competition. The entry fee for this competition is &euro;25,- per person,
 which is used to cover some of the costs for lunch, dinner, drinks and snacks throughout the day. You can either sign-up as a
 solo Android developer or designer or sign-up with a complete team. The ideal team consist of two Android developers and
 one designer (the top teams from last year had two developers and a designer on board), but teams of three Android developers
 are allowed as well. We encourage Android development companies to register and sponsor their own team!</p>

<h2>Further information</h2>

<p>If you need further information about the hackathon or want to contact the organization about registering a company
team or other sponsoring possibilities please send an e-mail to <a href="info@dutchaug.org">info@dutchaug.org</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DutchAUG becomes a foundation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.dutchaug.org/blog/2013/02/05/dutchaug-becomes-a-foundation/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.dutchaug.org/blog/2013/02/05/dutchaug-becomes-a-foundation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we have registered <a href="https://plus.google.com/113182948271879290904">+The Dutch Android User Group</a> as an official foundation at the notary office this morning and at the chamber of
commerce later this week.</p>

<p>Formalising our initiative helps us in creating better content for you, the Dutch Android professional or hobbyist.
By becoming a foundation we are better equiped to attract funds and are committed to give everything back to the Dutch Android community in the
form of meetups, open space meetings, hackathons, workshops, etc. We are excited, confident and looking forward
to continue to build the Dutch Android community with <em>Stichting</em> (Foundation in Dutch) The Dutch Android User Group in the upcoming years!</p>

<p>In the pictures, foundation board members <a href="https://plus.google.com/114227856179062761851">+Johan Pelgrim</a>,
<a href="https://plus.google.com/113269803670398336067">+Dennis Geurts</a> and <a href="https://plus.google.com/105209480109514753422">+Wiebe Elsinga</a> jotting down their signatures on the notary papers.</p>

<p><img src="/images/news/IMG_20130205_110757.jpg"><img src="/images/news/IMG_20130205_110809.jpg"><img src="/images/news/IMG_20130205_110821.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
